Guide to the Frieda Schwenkmeyer Collection on the Henry Street Settlement Strike WAG.147
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Frieda Schwenkmeyer Collection on the Henry Street Settlement Strike
Bulk, 1965
1963-1993
WAG.147
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
1.0 linear feet in 1 record carton
Frieda Schwenkmeyer (1901- ) was a labor organizer from Cincinnati, Ohio. In 1965 the Henry Street Settlement social workers went on strike for over two months, demanding a single bargaining unit encompassing all workers. This collection contains correspondence, flyers, petitions, meeting notes, picket schedules, clippings, and a small amount of financial records.
Schwenkmeyer, Frieda
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Materials found in collection; provenance is unknown. The accession number 1950.258 is associated with this collection.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. Materials are in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Historical/Biographical Note
Frieda Schwenkmeyer (1901- ) was a labor organizer from Cincinnati, Ohio. Over the course of her career Schwenkmeyer worked for the YWCA, the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, the United Electrical Workers and the Henry Street Settlement.
The Henry Street Settlement is a social service agency located in the Lower East Side, which was founded by Lillian Wald in 1893. The Settlement provides social services, arts programming and health care to New Yorkers at 17 difference locations. In 1965 the Henry Street Settlement social workers went on strike for over two months, demanding a single bargaining unit encompassing all workers (both permanent staff and special project staff employeed through foundation or government funding).
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains correspondence, flyers, petitions, meeting notes, picket schedules, clippings, and a small amount of financial records.
AFSCME. District Council 1707.; Henry Street Settlement (New York, N.Y.).; Collective labor agreements |x Social workers.; Social settlements |z New York (State) |z New York.; Social workers |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.; Strikes and lockouts |x Social workers.
- [Background: Henry Street Settlement History], 1992-1993 (Box 1)
- Picketing Schedules, 1965 (Box 1)
- Names and Addresses, undated (Box 1)
- Neighborhood Support, 1965 (Box 1)
- Newspaper Coverage, 1965 (Box 1)
- Letters to Staff, 1964 (Box 1)
- American Civil Liberties Union, 1964 (Box 1)
- Leaflets, 1964 (Box 1)
- Letters to and from Board, 1964 (Box 1)
- Playhouse and Music School, 1965 (Box 1)
- Loudspeaker, undated (Box 1)
- Schedules, 1965 (Box 1)
- Emergency Services, undated (Box 1)
- [Commentary], 1965 (Box 1)
- Community People, undated (Box 1)
- Strategy Suggestions, undated (Box 1)
- Songs, undated (Box 1)
- [Correspondence], 1963-1966 (Box 1)
- Helen Hall Letter, 1965 (Box 1)
- Flyer: Suggestions, undated (Box 1)
- Letters to Influentials, 1965 (Box 1)
- [Correspondence], 1964-1965 (Box 1)
- Community and Outside Letters, 1965 (Box 1)
- Union Flyers, 1965 (Box 1)
- Staff Lists, undated (Box 1)
- Petitions, undated (Box 1)
- Letters to Professionals, 1965 (Box 1)
- [Miscellaneous], 1964-1965 (Box 1)
- [Miscellaneous], 1964-1965 (Box 1)
- [Miscelllaneous], undated (Box 1)
- [Miscellaneous], undated (Box 1)
- [Frieda Schwenkmeyer Oral History Transcript], 1978 (Box 1)